Christian Howe

PROFILE

I have been programming for 13 years, starting at the age of 12. I am interested in working with iOS mobile software, web development, and software engineering, especially in a functional style. My especially broad knowledge and high adaptability is due to much of my experience coming from personal experience in open source. I am looking for full-time position in front-end or full-stack software engineering.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THE NEW OFFICE, AUSTIN, TX JAN 2016 - DEC 2016 I worked on an Elm frontend and Elixir backend for data integration technology. This included doing a major pull request over many weeks to add support for connecting to a distributed MongoDB topology by conforming to their client specification.

SUPPORT ENGINEER, NODEJITSU; REMOTE MAR 2012 - APR 2013 I started this job in high school, where I worked on Github pull requests for Node.js backend server software while providing technical support to other engineers using the hosting platform. Nodejitsu was bought out by GoDaddy.

FREELANCER, REMOTE 2012 - PRESENT

I have been freelancing on and off since I started programming. These projects include iOS mobile applications, React, Redux and GraphQL full-stack websites, mobile and desktop cryptocurrency clients in Qt, and many other smaller projects in Unity 3D and other technologies.

EDUCATION

VIRGINIA TECH - COMPUTER SCIENCE, FALL 2018 (EXPECTED)

SKILLS

| • | iOS, | XCode, | Swift, | MVC |
|---|------|--------|--------|-----|
|---|------|--------|--------|-----|

Implementing mockup designs

Javascript/ES6 (babel, webpack)

Functional Programming

Node.is and npm/yarn

· Elixir, OTP, distributed systems

React, Redux, Next.js, Gatsby

Git/Github and open source

RxJS, RxSwift, MVVM

MongoDB, SQL, Firebase

GraphQL/Apollo

Fast learner, adaptable

HTML, CSS and SASS

· Linux, OS X and Windows